Inventory of the San Francisco Public Library collection
Hoover Institution Archives
San Francisco Public Library collection
1885-1945
2002C30
Hoover Institution Archives
6 cubic foot boxes (6.0 linear feet)
Pamphlets relating primarily to World Wars I and II in Europe and to other aspects of 20th century European history. Collected by the San Francisco Public Library.
San Francisco Public Library
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The San Francisco Public Library opened in 1879 after the Rogers Act, which created a board of trustees and a property tax to fund the library, was enacted by Governor William Irwin. In 2015, the main library and 27 branch libraries make up the public library system of the city of San Francisco, California.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of pamphlets relating primarily to World War I and World War II in Europe, and some relating to 20th century European history in general. These pamphlets were collected by the San Francisco Public Library and bound into books based on their respective categories. The titles are those given by the Library.
San Francisco Public Library.; Europe--History--20th century.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Alsace-Lorraine Historical Pamphlets, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - "The Annexation of Alsace-Lorraine and Its Recovery, with an Address by Marshal Joffre,", 1918
  - "La Question D'Alsace-Lorraine en 1918,"
  - "Alsace-Lorraine French Land,", 1918
  - "The Inviolable Pledge,", 1918
  - "Present Day Life in Alsace. Both Within and Beyond Our Lines,", undated
  - "Les departements envahis, d'Alsace & de Lorraine,", undated
  - "The Future of Alsace-Lorraine,", 1917
  - "Alsace and Lorraine on the Eve of Deliverance,", 1917
  - "Three Days in Reconquered Alsace,", 1918
  - "Alsace-Lorraine Protests,", undated
  - "Questions d'Alsace-Lorraine,", 1918
- Belgium in the European War, 1914-1918 (Box 1)
  - "The Commission for Relief in Belgium: The Organization,", 1915
  - "The Commission for Relief in Belgium: Report of Captain J.F. Lucey,", 1915
  - "The Commission for Relief in Belgium: Address by Mr. Lindon W. Bates,", 1915
  - "History of the Woman's Section of the Commission for Relief in Belgium,", 1914
  - "Crowns for the Valiant,", undated
  - "The Condition of the Belgian Workmen now Refugees in England,", 1917
  - "Handbook Issued by the Commission for Relief in Belgium,", undated
  - "The Need of Belgium,", undated
  - "Great Britain and Supplies for Belgian Industries,", 1916
  - "Reports on the Violation of the Rights of Nations and of the Laws and Customs of War in Belgium,", undated
  - "Reports on the Violation of the Rights of Nations and of the Laws and Customs of War in Belgium, Volume II,", undated
  - "The Violation of the Neutrality of Belgium,", 1915
  - "The Second Belgium Grey Book,", 1915
  - "Diplomatic Correspondence Respecting the War Published by the Belgian Government,", 1914
  - "An Eye-Witness at Louvain,", 1914
  - "Facts about Belgium,", undated
  - "German Posters in Belgium: Their Value as Evidence,", 1918
  - "Unemployment in Belgium during the German Occupation and its General Causes,", 1917
- Belgium in the European War Pamphlets, 2d Series, 1916-1929 (Box 1)
  - "L'oeuvre du gouvernement Belge. Pendant la Guerre. Par le Bureau Documentaire Belge,", 1917
  - "For Our Soldiers! Address by His Eminence Cardinal Mercier,", 1916
  - "To Belgium,", 1916
  - "Administrative Separation, What Belgians in Invaded Belgium Think of It,", 1918
  - "Memorandum of the Belgian Government on the Deportation and Forced Labour of the Belgian Civil Population Ordered by the German Government,", undated
  - "August the Fourth, 1914 in the Belgian Parliament,", 1918
  - "The Legend of the 'Francs-Tireurs' of Louvain,", 1928
  - "Through the Iron Bars,", 1917
  - "Fete Nationale Belge--Belgian Independence Day,", 1916
  - "A Neutral Description of the Sack of Louvain,", 1929
  - "The Unconquerable Soul. Belgium in War Time,", 1918
  - "The Enslavement of Belgians--A Protest,", 1916
  - "The Innocence of Belgium, Established by the Military Documents Published by Germany,", undated
  - "The Belgians in Holland, 1914-1917,"
  - "The Martyrdom of Belgium. Official Report of Massacres of Peaceable Citizens, Women and Children by the German Army,", undated
  - "Why Belgium Was Devastated as Recorded in Proclamations of the German Commanders in Belgium,", undated
  - "Rapport succinct sur l'etat du palais des academies apres le depart des allemands, par Louis le Nain,", 1919
- Czechoslovak Historical Pamphlets, 1919 (Box 1)
  - "The Peace League of George Podebrad, King of Bohemia,", 1919
  - "La Ville de Prague. Apercu Historique. Par le Dr. Venceslas Vojtisek,", 1919
  - "Magyars and the Czecho-Slovak Republic. Their Past and Present Relations,", 1919
  - "Czecho-Slovak Secondary Schools,", 1919
  - "La Slovaquie, Terre de l'Avenir. Par Karel Kalal,", 1919
  - "Polaci a Ceskoslovenska Republika,", 1919
  - "Karpatska Rus. Inz. Alois Hora,", 1919
  - "Ceske Kladsko,", 1919
  - "Madari A Ceskoslovenska Republika,", 1919
  - "Slovensko, zeme budoucnosti,", 1919
  - "Podkarpatska Rus,", 1919
  - "Zdejin Mesta Prahy,", 1919
  - "Jihoslovane A Ceskoslovenska Republika,", 1919
  - "Organisace Statni spravy Podkarpatske,", 1919
  - "Prehled politickych Stran V Cechach,", 1919
  - "Organisace Statni Spravy Podkarpatske Rusi. II,", 1919
  - "Zahranici obchod Ceskoslovenskeho statu,", 1919
  - "Ze Zakonne Socialni Pece v uzemi Ceskoslovenske republiky pred valkou a za valky,", 1919
- Czechoslovakia Historical Pamphlet, 2d Series, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - "The Bohemians (Czechs) in the Present Crisis. Address by Charles Pergler, 28th Day of May 1916,"
  - "Declaration of the Bohemian (Czech) Foreign Committee,", undated
  - "Bohemia's Claim to Independence,", 1916
  - "The Slavs Among the Nations,", 1916
  - "The Case of Bohemia,", undated
  - "Detruisez l'Autriche-Hongrie!,", undated
  - "Bohemian (Czech) Hopes and Aspirations,", 1916
  - "Great Britain and the Czecho-Slovaks,", undated
  - "Prussian Upper Silesia and the Czech State,", undated
  - "Tesin Silesia, an Integrant Part of the Czech State,", undated
  - "Great Czecho-Slovaks. President of the Czecho-Slovak Republic Thomas G. Masaryk,", undated
  - "The Diplomatic Struggle for European Security and the Stabilization of Peace,", undated
  - "President Masaryk and the Spirit of Abraham Lincoln,", undated
  - "Bohemia. A Brief Evaluation of Bohemia's Contribution to Civilization,", 1917
  - "Heroic Story of the Czecho-Slovak Legions,", undated
- Czechoslovakia Miscellaneous Publications, 1941, 1944, undated (Box 1)
  - "Labour Legislation in the Czechoslovak Mining Industry,", 1944
  - "Democracy in Czechoslovakia,", 1941
  - "Czechoslovak Catholics,", undated
  - "Czechoslovak Before and After Munich,", undated
- Free Czechoslovakia in Free Europe, 1940-1942 (Box 1)
  - "German Cultural Oppression in Czechoslovakia,", 1940
  - "The Story of Two Peoples, or, Czechoslovak and German Morality,", 1942
  - "Germany's Economic Conquest of Czechoslovakia,", undated
  - "Nazi Barbarism in Czechoslovakia,", undated
  - "Czechoslovakia, Its Sacrifice and Future,", undated
- Eastern Question Pamphlets, 2d Series, 1916-1935 (Box 1)
  - "Albania's Rights and Claims to Independence and Territorial Integrity,", 1918
  - "Albania's Rights, Hopes and Aspirations. The Strength of the National Consciousness of the Albanian People,", 1918
  - "Poland Under the Germans,", 1916
  - "The Policy of National Instinct,", 1915
  - "Pages Roumaines,", 1918
  - "La Dobroudja,", 1918
  - "The Macedonian Slavs: Their National Character and Struggles,", 1927
  - "Memorandum Presented by the Greek Members of the Turkish Parliament to the American Commission on Mandates Over Turkey,", 1919
  - "Deutschland uber Allah,", 1917
  - "The Ottoman Domination,", 1917
  - "Treaty Revision and the Hungarian Frontiers,", 1934
  - "The Destruction of Poland, a Study of German Efficiency,", 1916
  - "Lithuania: Facts Supporting Her Claim for Reestablishment as an Independent Nation,", 1918
  - "The Justice of Rumania's Cause,", 1917
  - "Greater Rumania: A Study in National Ideals,", 1917
  - "Memorandum. Addressed to the Peace Conference,", 1919
  - "We the Macedonians,", 1919
  - "Dr. Kadlec Karoly Tanar: A Magyarok es a Cseh-Szlovak Koztarsasag,", 1919
  - "Justice for Hungary,", 1935
  - "The Last Stronghold of Old-World Tradition: The Principality of Liechtenstein,", 1935
  - "Report of the Inter-Allied Commission in Eastern Macedonia, Part I. Account of Bulgarian Occupation,", 1919
  - "The Case of Kurdistan Against Turkey,", 1928
- European War Economic Pamphlets, 1917-1919 (Box 1)
  - "The War Business in the United States,", undated
  - "British Workshops and the War,", 1917
  - "The World's Largest Loan,", 1917
  - "Industrial France and the War,", undated
  - "The Economic Weapon in the War Against Germany,", 1918
  - "Britain's Financial Effort,", undated
  - "German Business and German Aggression,", 1918
  - "British Railways and the War,", 1917
  - "Governmental War Agencies Affecting Business,", 1918
  - "Trading with the Enemy,", 1918
  - "A Report of the Activities of the War Department in the Field of Industrial Relations During the War,", 1919
- European War Pamphlets, 1st Series, 1915, undated (Box 1)
  - "Kaiser, Krupp and Kultur,", 1915
  - "Thou Art the Man,", undated
  - "The Imprisonment of the Ghent Professors,", undated
  - "Messages, Discours-Allocutions, Lettres et Telegrammes,", 1915
- European War Pamphlets, 2d Series, 1914-1915, undated (Box 2)
  - "The Foreign Policy of Sir Edward Grey, 1906-1915,"
  - "The Balfour Visit,", undated
  - "Their Crimes,", undated
  - "The Pirate's Progress,", undated
  - "L'effort Charitable Des Etats-Unis,", undated
  - "Britain and Turkey, the Causes of the Rupture,", undated
  - "When the War Will End,", undated
  - "Canada to Ireland,", undated
  - "Why Italy Is With the Allies,", undated
  - "British Civilian Prisoners in German East Africa,", undated
  - "How Britain Strove for Peace,", 1914
- European War Pamphlets, 3d Series, 1914-1915 (Box 2)
  - "Belgium. The Second Belgian Grey Book,", 1915
  - "Austro-Hungarian Red Book,", undated
  - "Great Britain. Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Diplomatic Correspondence Respecting the War,", 1914
  - "Great Britain. Committee on Alleged German Outrages,", 1915
- European War Pamphlets, 4th Series, 1915-1917 (Box 2)
  - "British and German Ideals,", undated
  - "The German Note and the Reply of the Allies,", 1917
  - "The Duel Alliance versus the Triple Entente,", undated
  - "How to Win the War,", 1917
  - "The New German Empire, From the Round Table,", 1917
  - "The Martyrdom of Belgium,", undated
  - "The Treatment of Prisoners of War in England and Germany,", 1915
  - "What is the Matter with England?,", 1915
  - "S.O.S.,", undated
  - "The German Atrocities in France,", 1915
- European War Pamphlets, 5th Series, 1915-1918 (Box 2)
  - "After Twelve Months of War,", 1915
  - "The British Blockade,", 1915
  - "How Do We Stand Today?,", 1915
  - "Some Comments on War Taxation,", 1917
  - "Government Ownership of Railroads and War Taxation,", 1918
  - "How Long Will It Last?,", 1916
  - "Submarines and Zeppelins in Warfare and Outrage,", 1916
  - "The Jutland Battle,", 1916
  - "The Germans and the Small Nations,", 1917
  - "Russia and Her Allies,", 1917
  - "The Verdict of India,", undated
  - "The Murderous Tyranny of the Turks,", 1917
  - "The Deportations of Belgian Workmen,", 1917
  - "German War Aims,", 1918
  - "British Staying Power,", 1918
  - "Militarism at Work in Belgium and Germany,", undated
- European War Pamphlets, 6th Series, 1918, undated (Box 2)
  - "The Crimes of Germany,", undated
  - "Belgium and Germany,", undated
  - "Reply to the German White Book of the 10th May, 1915,", 1918
- European War Pamphlets, 7th Series, 1914-1919 (Box 2)
  - "Canada's Part in the Great War,", 1919
  - "Some Facts about India,", 1917
  - "The Welfare of Egypt,", undated
  - "Americans at the Front,", undated
  - "Russia and Her Allies,", 1917
  - "The Care of the Dead,", 1916
  - "Trifling with the War,", 1918
  - "The Mails as a German War Weapon,", 1916
  - "Censorship and Trade,", 1916
  - "The Press Censorship,", 1916
  - "The Finances of Great Britain and Germany,", undated
  - "Why Mail Censorship is Vital to Britain,", 1916
  - "Russia: the Psychology of a Nation,", 1914
  - "The League of Nations: the Opportunity of the Church,", undated
  - "The War on Hospital Ships,", 1918
  - "Some Swedish Reflections,", 1916
  - "Britain Transformed,", undated
  - "An Economic Interpretation of the War,", 1915
  - "Damaging Evidence Against English Hypocrisy,", 1915
  - "Some Gains of the War,", 1918
- European War Pamphlets, 8th Series, 1914-1918 (Box 2)
  - "Our Just Cause,", undated
  - "Is War Civilization?,", 1917
  - "Color Blind Neutrality,", undated
  - "Loyal India,", 1916
  - "The Future of India,", 1916
  - "The Commercial Future of Baghdad,", 1917
  - "The Far East in the European War,", 1914
  - "Germany's Economic Power of Resistance,", 1916
  - "The War and Business,", 1917
  - "Frenzied Liberty: The Myth of a Rich Man's War,", 1918
- European War Pamphlets, 9th Series, 1917-1918, 1925 (Box 2)
  - "British Censorship and Enemy Publications,", 1917
  - "The Woman's Part,", undated
  - "Japan to Her Allies,", 1917
  - "The Stabilization of the Price of Wheat During the War and Its Effects Upon the Returns to the Producer,", 1925
  - "Lafayette Escadrille Memorial," pamphlet, undated
  - "One Nation--One Cause,", 1918
  - "Win-the-War Cartoons,", undated
- European War Pamphlets, 10th Series, 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - "In the Land of Death,", 1917
  - "General Von Bissing's Testament: A Study in German Ideals,", undated
  - "German Atrocities from German Evidence,", undated
  - "How Germany Seeks to Justify Her Atrocities,", undated
  - "The German War and Catholicism,", 1916
  - "Les Allemands a Lille,", 1916
- European War Pamphlets, 11th Series, 1915-1918, 1932 (Box 2)
  - "No More Reparations,", 1932
  - "Moral Aspects of the European War,", 1917
  - "Who Wanted War?,", 1915
  - "The Violation by Germany of the Neutrality of Belgium and Luxemburg,", undated
  - "The First Violations of the Law of Nations by Germany: Luxemburg and Belgium,", 1917
  - "Collection of Evidence Concerning the Violations of International Law by the Countries at War with Austria-Hungary,", 1915
  - "Why We Went to War,", undated
  - "Le Liure d'Or des Canadiens,", 1915
  - "The Case of Egypt,", undated
  - "The Imperial Russian Finances,", undated
  - "Austria-Hungary and the War,", 1915
  - "The Russian Plot to Seize Galicia,", 1915
  - "The Ukraine and the Ukrainians,", 1915
  - "S.O.S.,", undated
  - "La Finlande,", 1918
  - "A Trip through Headline Land,", 1918
  - "Current Misconceptions about the War,", 1915
- European War Pamphlets, 12th Series, 1914-1919, 1923, 1932 (Box 3)
  - "On the Field of Honour: The Belgian Front on the Yser and the British Front in Flanders,", undated
  - "The Rockefeller Foundation,", 1915
  - "England, Germany, and Europe,", 1914
  - "German War Aims,", 1917
  - "Why the War Must Go On,", 1917
  - "Studies and Documents on the War 1815-1915 from the Congress of Vienna to the War of 1914,"
  - "The Visions of Mons and Ypres,", undated
  - "The Economic Dilemma of Politics,", 1932
  - "The Victory Drive,", undated
  - "Are Italy's Claims on Istria Dalmatia and Islands Justified?,", undated
  - "The Preparedness of America,", 1914
  - "Publications of the Virginia War History Commission,", 1923
  - "Allied War Exposition,", undated
  - "Treaty of Peace with Germany,", 1919
  - "Hungary and the War,", 1915
  - "Report of the Committee on Alleged German Outrages,", undated
  - "Despatches from His Majesty's Ambassador at Berlin Respecting an Official German Organisation for Influencing the Press of Other Countires,", 1914
  - "Documents Respecting the Negotiation Preceding the War Published by the Russian Government,", 1914
  - "Neutrality and Public Opinion,", 1915
- European War Pamphlets, 14th Series, 1916-1919, 1932 (Box 3)
  - "For the Defence of Venice,", 1918
  - "Primer and A.B.C. of Reparations and War Debts,", 1932
  - "Data on German Peace Treaty,", 1919
  - "Papers Relating to German Atrocities, and Breaches of the Rules of War, in Africa,", 1916
  - "Un Royaume en Exil,", undated
- European War Pamphlets, Campaigns and Battles, 1917, 1930, undated (Box 6)
  - "The Battle of the Somme, Second Phase,", undated
  - "The Keypoint of the Marne,", 1930
  - "The Deliverance of Jerusalem,", undated
  - "The War on Hospital Ships,", 1917
  - "The Victory of the Marne,", 1917
  - "Pen Pictures of British Battles,", 1917
- European War Pamphlets, Campaigns and Battles, 4th Series, 1915-1917, 1923 (Box 6)
  - "The Means of Victory,", 1916
  - "The War Message of President Wilson,", undated
  - "France et Allemagne,", 1915
  - "Six of One and Half-a-Dozen of the Other,", 1917
  - "The Events of July 1914,", undated
  - "The United States and This War: A Word in Season,", 1915
  - "Address Delivered at the Protest Meeting Against the Invasion of the Ruhr,", 1923
  - "La Guerra e La Guerra,", undated
- European War Pamphlets, Naval History, 1916-1918 (Box 3)
  - "Submarines and Zeppelins in Warfare and Outrage,", 1916
  - "Flying, Submarining and Mine Sweeping,", 1916
  - "The British Navy at War,", 1917
  - "The Pirate's Progress: A Short History of the U-Boat,", 1918
  - "The Fleets Behind the Fleet: The Work of the Merchant Seaman and Fisherman in the War,", 1917
  - "A Note on the History of Submarine War,", undated
- France Historical Pamphlets, 1885-1932 (Box 3)
  - "La Chronique de France,", 1904
  - "Two Histories Face to Face. France vs. Germany,", 1919
  - "Vergennes et l'independance americaine. Vergennes & Wilson,", 1918
  - "Operations of the French Navy during the Recent War with Tunis. 1880-1881,", 1885
  - "Fair Play for France,", 1932
  - "The Ruhr Problem. An Independent Rhineland Westpahia,", 1923
  - "Revue de l'histoire des Colonies Francoises,", 1915
- France in the European War Pamphlets, 2d Series, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
  - "From Lafayette to Pershing,", undated
  - "Les Monuments Francais, Detruits par L'Allemagne,", 1918
  - "France Amerique,", 1918
  - "Exposition de Guerre. Guide souvenir illustre,", 1917
  - "La Gloire de la France,", undated
  - "Scraps of Paper: German Proclamation in Belgium and France,", undated
- German History Pamphlets, 1914-1936 (Box 3)
  - "The Austro-German Customs Union Project,", 1931
  - "My Misson to London 1912-1914,", undated
  - "A Letter to a Hitlerite,", 1934
  - "What Herr Hitler Did Not Want the English Speaking Countries to Know,", undated
  - "Hitlerism and Our Liberties,", 1934
  - "Equality,", 1936
  - "Hitler and Arms,", undated
  - "Hitlerism: Why and Whither,", 1934
  - "Grossere Deutschland,", 1914
  - "Deutschland Unter den Weltvolfern,", 1921
- Germany in the European War, 1915-1918 (Box 3)
  - "The Poison Growth of Prussianism,", 1918
  - "Le Memoire Lichnowsky,", undated
  - "German Women and the War,", 1918
  - "Germany's Colonial Failture,", 1918
  - "Revelations of an Ex-Director of Krupp's,", undated
  - "A Slanderer,", undated
  - "The German Empire of Central Africa,", undated
  - "Jews and Germanism,", undated
  - "Subject Nationalities of the German Alliance,", 1917
  - "Germany's Food Supply,", 1916
  - "Germany Above All,", 1915
  - "Disclosures of a German Staff Officer,", 1918
  - "Pan-Germanism,", 1915
  - "Truth About Germany; Facts About the War,", undated
- Germany in the European War Pamphlets, 3d Series, 1916-1918, undated (Box 3)
  - "The German Colonies. What Is to Become of Them?,", 1918
  - "The Pan-Germanism Programme. The Petition of the Six Associations and the Manifesto of the Intellectuals,", undated
  - "General Smuts's Message to South Wales,", undated
  - "Germany Her Own Judge,", 1918
  - "The German Chancellor and the Outbreak of the War,", undated
  - "German Opinion and German Policy Before the War,", undated
  - "The German War Code,", undated
  - "Les Allemends a Lille et ans Le Nord De La France. Ministere des Affaires Strangeres,", 1916
- Germany in the European War Pamphlets, 4th Series, 1914-1916, 1921 (Box 4)
  - "Kriegsbriefe Deutscher Studenten,", 1916
  - "Germans as Exponents of Culture,", 1914
  - "Search-Lights on the War,", 1915
  - "The German White-book. How Russia and Her Ruler Betrayed Germany's Confidence and thereby Caused the European War,", undated
  - "The Belgian People's War, a Violation of International Law,", 1915
  - "Die Wahrheit Uber Die Deutschen Kriegs Verbrechen,", 1921
  - "Bernhardi Converted. A Comparative Study of the Effect of Drastic Medicine on the Expressed Opinions of General von Bernhardi,", 1915
- Germany in the European War Pamphlets, 5th Series, 1914-1918 (Box 4)
  - "The German Pirate,", 1918
  - "The Black Slaves of Prussia,", 1918
  - "A Reprint of the Thyssen,", 1918
  - "Revelations by an Ex-Director of Krupp's,", 1918
  - "Anti-Semitism in Germany,", 1918
  - "Truth About Germany. Facts About War,", undated
  - "Search-Lights on the War,", 1915
  - "Current Misconceptions About the War,", 1915
  - "German War Finance,", 1916
  - "Meine Londoner Mission, 1912-1914,", undated
  - "Germany's Hour of Destiny,", 1914
  - "How Russia and Her Ruler Betrayed Germany's Confidences and Thereby Caused the European War,", 1914
  - "Report of the Committee on Alleged German Outrages, Appointed by His Britannic Majesty's Government,", 1914
- German Politics and Governments Pamphlets, 1935-1937 (Box 4)
  - "Passing Through Germany, 10th ed.,", 1936
  - "The Nazi Party, the State and Religion, by Adolf Hitler,", undated
  - "Germany's Foreign Policy, as Stated in Mein Kampf,", undated
  - "Our National Socialism and World Relations,", 1937
  - "Germany Rearms in the Air,", 1935
  - "Education Under the Nazis,", 1936
  - "Culture Under the Nazis,", 1936
- Great Britain Foreign Office European War Documents, 1914-1918 (Box 4)
  - "Correspondence Respecting the European Crisis,", 1914
  - "Despatch from H.M. Ambassador at Berlin Respecting the Rupture of Diplomatic Relations with the German Government,", 1914
  - "Despatch from H.M. Ambassador at Vienna Respecting the Rupture of Diplomatic Relations with the German Government,", 1914
  - "Correspondence Respecting Events Leading to the Rupture of Relations with Turkey,", 1914
  - "Despatch from H.M. Ambassador at Constantinople Summarising Events Leading Up to Rupture of Relations with Turkey, and Reply Thereto,", 1914
  - "Correspondence between H.M. Government and the U.S. Ambassador Respecting the Treatment of German Prisoners of War and Interned Civilians in the United Kingdom,", 1915